Love rules all.
The Young Victoria is a drama, history, romance
film directed by Jean-Marc Vallée.
As the only legitimate heir of England's King William, teenage Victoria gets
caught up in the political machinations of her own family.
Victoria's mother wants her to sign a regency order, while her Belgian uncle schemes to arrange a marriage
between the future monarch and Prince Albert, the man who will become the love of her life.
Queen Victoria, played by Emily Blunt.
Prince Albert, played by Rupert Friend.
Lord Melbourne, played by Paul Bettany.
Duchess of Kent, played by Miranda Richardson.
King William IV, played by Jim Broadbent.
King Leopold, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
The Young Victoria is a 2009 British period drama film directed by Jean-Marc Vallée and written by Julian Fellowes, based
on the early life and reign of Queen Victoria, and her marriage to Prince Albert of Saxe-Coburg and Gotha.
Produced by Graham King, Martin Scorsese, Sarah Ferguson, and Timothy Headington, the film stars Emily Blunt, Rupert Friend,
Paul Bettany, Miranda Richardson, Harriet Walter, Mark Strong, and Jim Broadbent among a large ensemble cast.
As screenwriter, Fellowes sought to make the film as
historically accurate as possible.
With this in mind, Oscar-winning costume designer Sandy Powell and historical consultant Alastair Bruce were hired, and filming
for The Young Victoria took place at various historical landmarks in England to further the film's authenticity.
Despite this, some aspects of the film have been
criticised for their historical inaccuracies.
Momentum Pictures released the film in the United Kingdom and Sony Pictures Worldwide Acquisitions
Group opened The Young Victoria in limited theatrical release in the United States.
Critical reception was generally positive.
The film explores themes of royal family, biography,
royalty, period drama, 19th century.
The tone is emotional.